we are on the home stretch well done for
我们正在为做得好做最后冲刺
sticking with the series it's uh it's a
坚持这个系列 呃 这是一个
lot of work a lot to uh retain but uh
有很多工作要做 呃要留住 但是呃
well done for sticking with it now a
做得好因为现在坚持它而成为
couple of things before we jump into
在我们开始讨论之前 有几件事
compositing the fun compositing stuff um
合成有趣的合成东西嗯
I noticed a couple of things that I
我注意到几件事 我
could tweak to the lighting just to
可以调整到灯光只是为了
improve it and it's important we do it
改善它 我们做这件事很重要
now because what we're going to do next
因为我们接下来要做的是
relies on the lighting being uh correct
依赖于照明是否呃正确
so um the first is I noticed that the
所以 嗯 第一 我注意到
the light rotation it would be a little
光的自转会有一点
bit better if I rotated it so it's
如果我把它旋转一下会更好一些
almost like a 90° like completely side
几乎像90度完全一样的边
onto the donuts um so that's pretty
放在甜甜圈上 嗯 很漂亮
simple change the other one I noticed is
我注意到的另一个简单的改变是
that I'm getting this like kind of ugly
我变得有点难看了
bounce light coming off this uh both the
反射光从这个 呃 都
plate and the table so to fix that I can
盘子和桌子 这样我就可以
just move right go into edit mode Edge
只需向右移动进入编辑模式边缘
select mode select the edge of this
选择模式选择这条边
window and then if I just drag drag it
窗口 然后如果我只是拖拽它
you'll see that the light just
你会看到光就在
disappears off the front there and now I
从前线消失了 现在我
have controlled the light now the other
现在已经控制了另一个人的光
thing speaking of control I notice
说到控制 我注意到了
looking at this wall like I was trying
看着这面墙 就像我在努力
to tweak it and just try to improve it
去调整它 试着改进它
but this is like a huge uh source of
但这就像是一个巨大的 呃来源
light right and so if you look on our
灯光向右 所以如果你看我们的
donut it's not very controlled right I
但甜甜圈不是很受控制 对吗？
could either if I if I want to fill in
我也可以 如果我想填
this space I could increase the
这个空间我可以增加
brightness of that wall but you can see
那面墙的亮度 但你可以看到
it just it throws light just everywhere
它只是它投射的光到处都是
and I don't really have any control over
我真的不能控制
it so change my mind let's not use that
它改变了我的想法 我们不要再用它了
as a fill Source let's just drop the
作为填充源 我们只需删除
value to zero so there is now no light
值设置为零 因此现在没有灯光
coming off of that wall it is a black
从那堵墙下来 它是一块黑色的
void um which is actually pretty I mean
空虚 实际上很漂亮 我的意思是
that's like a photographer holding up a
这就像一个摄影师举着一张
black uh fill card next to her face uh
黑色的 嗯 在她的脸上填卡片 嗯
and
和
instead excuse
相反 借口
me okay quick break there had to get a
我好的 快点休息一下 必须要有一个
drink of water
喝水
instead I'm going to add in a lamp Okay
相反 我要加一盏灯 好的
so I'm going to shift right Mouse click
所以我要用鼠标右键点击
so that I drop it on the ground here in
所以我把它扔在这里的地上
front uh sorry to the side and then I'm
前面 呃 对不起 站在一边 然后我
going to go shift a and I'm going to add
我要去换班了 我要加上
in not a point lamp not a sun but an
不是点灯 不是太阳 而是
area lamp Okay so this is this is what
区域灯好的 这就是
it looks like it's just it looks like a
它看起来只是它看起来像一个
plane right flat Square thing and it
平面右平方的东西和它
casts it in the direction of that Arrow
向那个箭头的方向投射它
so I want to rotate it along the Y AIS
所以我想把它沿着Y轴旋转
just holding down control and in the top
只需按住Ctrl键并在顶部
left you can see we get a 90 ° angle so
向左你可以看到我们得到了一个90°的角度
that's what I'm looking for and then the
这就是我要找的 然后
size of this I want to drop the size in
这个的大小我想把大小放进去
the setting there okay so I just can go
那里的环境很好 所以我可以走了
really small
真的很小
actually and now if I pull in close with
实际上 现在如果我靠近
render View mode we should see a lot
渲染视图模式我们应该会看到很多内容
more
更多
control over where that fill light goes
控制填充光的去向
all right so I can pull it in nice and
好的 这样我就可以好好地把它拉进去
close right now that's obviously way too
现在就关门 那显然也太
bright so I'll just now dial that
太好了 我现在就拨那个
back like so and I can now pull it
像这样退后 我现在可以拉它了
forward forward so that I get the fill
向前走 这样我才能填饱肚子
light exactly where I want but that's
照亮我想要的地方 但那是
you know that's 3D right you try out an
你知道那是3D的 对 你试一试
idea you're like okay that could work
你的想法是 好的 这可能行得通
and then you look at and you're like H
然后你看着 你就像H
maybe not you know I'll try a different
也许不是 你知道 我会尝试不同的
one um but yeah so I'm just going to
一个 嗯 但好的 所以我要
give it a bit of a yellowy tint and
给它一点黄色 然后
that's better awesome okay so now we can
这样好多了 太棒了 现在我们可以
do some compositing first of all what is
先做一些合成 首先是什么
it well the compositor is a way to add
很好 排序器是一种加法
effects to the final render so that
效果添加到最终渲染 以便
could be everything from a simple color
可能是从简单的颜色到所有东西
grade to like really stylized uh renders
等级到喜欢非常风格化的呃渲染
so in our case we're going to use it to
因此在我们的案例中 我们将使用它来
add glare to better emulate a camera
添加眩光以更好地模拟相机
that's really the purpose for this
这就是我们这么做的目的
tutorial so at the top of your screen
教程 因此在您的屏幕顶部
click on the compositor tab so this will
单击合成器选项卡 这样这将
arrange your screen again disorient you
再次排列屏幕会让你迷失方向
for a moment um but yeah wouldn't you
有那么一会儿 嗯 但你不会吗
believe it it's another node screen so
相信它 这是另一个节点屏幕 所以
click use nodes at the top there for
单击顶部的使用节点用于
whatever reason they always appear off
不管是什么原因 他们总是显得不对劲
your screen um at least in my case maybe
你的屏幕 嗯 至少在我的情况下可能
it it appears on yours but if you middle
如果它出现在你的身上 但如果你居中
Mouse up or just scroll down you should
鼠标向上或向下滚动 您应该
be able to see it or you can just hit
能够看到它 或者你可以直接击打
the home key as well and that'll bring
家里的钥匙也一样 这将带来
it into Focus so it's actually pretty
它聚焦在焦点上 所以它实际上很漂亮
similar to like geometry nodes in that
类似于其中的类似几何体节点
on the left hand side this is your
在左手边这是你的
original like what you've started with
原创 就像你开始做的那样
your original render and then on the
您的原始渲染 然后在
right hand side um it's going to be your
右手边 嗯 它将是你的
final output like that's what's uh going
最终的输出就是这样 呃 就是这样
to be saved to an image and then in
要保存到图像 然后在
between here you can put whatever it is
在这里之间 你可以把任何东西
you want you could put um a a color
你想要的话你可以给她涂上颜色
grade you could do some post processing
等级 你可以做一些后处理
glare and shine and things like that um
眩光和闪光之类的东西 嗯
but before we can see anything because
但在我们看到任何东西之前 因为
normally you would see your result here
通常情况下 您会在此处看到结果
we can't for two reasons the first is we
我们做不到有两个原因 第一是我们
haven't done a render okay it's not
还没有做渲染 好的 不是的
enough to just look in like rendered
足以让人看起来就像是渲染的
View mode here right this is just like a
这里的查看模式就像是
temporary view whilst we're moving
在我们移动时的临时视野
around we have to do a proper render by
我们必须通过以下方式进行适当的渲染
hitting F12 but if we did one right now
按F12 但如果我们现在做一次
we would have we'd be waiting a while
我们会等上一段时间
because the maximum samples is 4,000
因为最大样本是4,000个
which is maybe it's like probably pretty
这可能是因为它很可能很漂亮
good for like film animation production
适合制作类似的电影动画
quality but it's Overkill and especially
质量 但它是过度的 特别是
for um for this like we're just doing
对于这个 就像我们正在做的那样
some test renders so let's set it to 100
一些测试渲染 所以让我们将其设置为100
samples and that'll do it way faster so
样品 这样做会更快 所以
now let's hit F12 on that there we go so
现在让我们在上面按F12键 我们开始了
that came through for me 7 seconds again
我又一次想到了7秒
I got 4 309s it'll probably be a little
我有4309 可能会有一点
slower if you're on a laptop but yeah
如果你使用笔记本电脑 速度会更慢 但是的
just you know be patient it'll it'll
只是你知道 要有耐心 它会的
come through now go to the compositing
现在过来 去做合成
tab and we still can't see it because we
标签 我们仍然看不到它 因为我们
need to add a viewer node um and connect
需要添加查看器节点um并连接
it to this and you can do that just by
到这个 你只需通过
holding down controll shift and then
按住Ctrl Shift然后
left clicking on your render layer and
在您的渲染层上单击鼠标左键
now we have a viewer node and in the
现在我们有了一个查看器节点 并且在
background we have our render so some
背景我们有我们的渲染 所以有些
people find it like a little weird to
人们觉得这有点奇怪
have the render in the background you
让渲染在后台进行
can move it around just by holding down
只需按住它就可以移动它
alt and then middle Mouse button and
Alt 然后按鼠标中键和
then middle Mouse button will move your
然后鼠标中键将移动您的
nodes around so alt middle Mouse button
节点周围 因此使用Alt鼠标中键
for the background and then uh middle
作为背景 然后 呃 中间
Mouse for the nodes anyways as a very
鼠标换来的节点无论如何都是非常的
quick example let's do a simple color
快速示例 让我们做一个简单的颜色
adjustment so adjustment color balance
调整以便调整颜色平衡
right drop this in here now the if you
好的 现在把这个放在这里 如果你
just dropped it into your viewer node
只需将其放入您的查看器节点
then this would be just what is going to
那么这就是将会发生的事情
be shown in the background here but it
在这里的背景中显示 但它
wouldn't be saved in your render until
不会保存在渲染中 直到
it went through your composite uh node
它穿过了你的复合体呃节点
but for just this quick effect it's uh
但仅仅为了这个快速的效果 它是呃
it's good enough so this is a um graders
它足够好了 所以这是一个嗯 评分员
know exactly what this is but it's for
我很清楚这是什么 但这是为了
uh on the left hand side your your
呃 在左手边 你的
blacks right uh your midtones is in the
黑人对 呃 你的中间色调在
middle and the right hand side is your
中间和右侧是您的
highlights so if I wanted to make uh you
亮点所以如果我想让你
know I don't know like a cooler midtone
我不知道是不是更酷的中间色调
and then like a warmer highlight right
然后像一个更温暖的突出显示
and then I don't know something for the
然后我也不知道该怎么做
blacks like make it more green I don't
黑色让它变得更绿我不喜欢
know just make something horrible you
知道只会让你变得很可怕
could do it here you could make simple
可以在这里做 你可以让它变得简单
color adjustments you could do it there
颜色调整你可以在那里做
and your your original render hasn't
而你的原始渲染并没有
changed this is just a postprocessing
更改后 这只是一个后处理
step but actually on the note of making
脚步 但实际上是在音符上
things look uh more contrasted and
事情看起来 呃 更反差和
Punchy I wouldn't actually bother with
我其实不会费心去做的
the color balance note we used to but uh
我们曾经用过的色彩平衡音符 但是
now now blender has some pretty good
现在搅拌机有一些很好的
color management so I'm going to hit
色彩管理 所以我要点击
controll X on that to just remove it but
按住X键将其移除 但是
retain its connection and then if you go
保持它的连接 然后如果你去
down in your render settings to color
在渲染设置中向下设置颜色
management uh there is um a look uh drop
管理 嗯 有一个眼神 嗯 下降
down here so if you set this to uh high
在这下面 如果你把这个调高
contrast that's exactly a the same as
对比一下 这和
like what we were doing there like
就像我们在那里做的那样
trying to like increase the highlights
试着增加亮点
or reduce the midtones it's a very
或者降低中间色调 这是一种非常
common thing to try and make something
试着做某事是很常见的
look punchier and these looks will do
看起来更有感染力 这些看起来就行了
that but do it really well um a lot of
但是做得很好 嗯 很多次
people make the assumption that this is
人们假设这是
like you shouldn't use these or it's
就像你不应该用这些 或者它
going to like mess with the colors in
我会喜欢把里面的颜色弄乱
some way and like other applications
在某种程度上和其他应用程序一样
true um a lot of uh like art apps they
是的 嗯 很多 呃 喜欢艺术应用 他们
just you know you you use one of their
只是你知道你用的是他们的其中一个
contrast settings and it just starts
对比度设置和它刚刚开始
like clipping highlights and things but
喜欢剪裁亮点之类的东西 但是
this was designed by Troy sabotka who
这是特洛伊·萨博特卡设计的
understands color science and color
了解色彩科学和色彩
management so it's a proper S curve you
管理 所以这是一条恰当的S曲线
won't have any clipping going on um so I
不会有任何剪辑 嗯 所以我
use this all the time usually the one I
一直用这个 通常我用的那个
go for is a medium high contrast look um
是中高对比度的看起来
and it just makes a really nice looking
它看起来真的很漂亮
result by the way just a quick mention
结果 顺便提一下 只是简单地提一下
in 4.0 this version of blender we
在4.0版本的搅拌机中 我们
switched the view transform through to
已将视图转换切换为
agx which creates more realistic uh
AGX哪个创造了更逼真的呢
looking images because previously it was
查看图像 因为以前是
on filmic and it looked like this and
在电影上 它看起来像这样
you can see the difference is
你可以看到区别在于
agx has it just looks more real um but
AGX有 只是看起来更真实 嗯 但是
the reason for that is that filmi was uh
原因是电影是呃
and actually the same with Aces right
实际上王牌也是如此 对吧
now the the film like the the the one
现在这部电影就像那部
the academy all the people in bfx shoes
学院所有的人都穿着BFX的鞋子
and everything it's got this same
它的一切都是一样的
problem but when uh you've got color the
问题是 当你有颜色的时候
more exposed a color is it should
更暴露的一种颜色是它应该
actually start to desaturate but what
实际上开始去饱和了 但是什么
Aces and what filmi was doing is it was
王牌和电影我所做的就是
making that color more and more
使这种颜色越来越多
saturated so that's why these bright
饱和所以这就是为什么这些明亮的
colors here are just starting to get
这里的色彩才刚刚开始变得
ugly right but agx fixes that and it
丑陋的对 但agx解决了这个问题
starts to behave more like film where it
开始表现得更像电影
desaturates those colors um as it
使那些颜色去饱和 因为它
exposes for so very cool um and I'm glad
太酷了 嗯 我很高兴
that they've got that while I'm here is
当我在这里的时候 他们得到的是
as well I'm just going to increase the
另外 我只需要增加
exposure a bit um it's going to blow it
曝光一点 嗯 它会搞砸的
out a little anyway we'll fix it a bit
不管怎样 我们会把它修好的
with the lighting uh later but anyways
灯光 呃 等会 但不管怎样
okay back to the
好的 回到
compositor so one thing that I often use
排版--这是我经常用到的一件事
the compositor for is for uh what you
排序器是用来 呃 你用的
see in the rear World which is glare
看后面的世界 那是耀眼的
right if you've got a shiny metallic
对 如果你有闪闪发亮的金属
object a bumper or something like that
反对保险杠之类的东西
you want to have that that Starburst
你想要那个星爆吗？
right coming off it because that's what
是正确的 因为这就是
you see in the real world you see it
你在现实世界中看到了它
both with your eyes like if you squinted
两个人的眼睛都像是眯着眼睛
something in the distance you'll see
在远处你会看到一些东西
like uh yeah like this kind of like
就像 嗯 对 就像这样
Starburst around like a street light at
星光闪耀 就像街灯一样
night that's actually because the
那实际上是因为
eyelashes on your eye but on a camera
眼睛上的睫毛 但相机上的睫毛
it's for a different reason it's because
这是另一个原因 因为
of the optical elements it's kind of
在光学元件中 它是一种
like refracting around itself and it's
就像在自己周围折射一样 它
creating this uh Starburst look I don't
创造这个呃星爆的造型我不是
understand it fully but I know that it's
完全理解 但我知道这是
an artifact which has artistic use as
艺术品一种具有艺术用途的艺术品
well um so we are going to add it it is
好吧 嗯 所以我们要添加它 它是
a little fiddly I'll be honest like
有点笨手笨脚的我会老实说
other software they just have a button
其他软件他们只有一个按钮
and it just like adds the bloom and the
就像是把花朵和花朵
glare and stuff
眩光之类的东西
we we have to do this for now so shift a
我们 我们现在必须这么做 所以转移一个
we probably could if more people donated
如果有更多的人捐献 我们或许可以
to blender right we could have stuff
正确地搅和 我们可以有一些东西
like this but anyways so not to guilt
就像这样 但不管怎样 不要内疚
you all filter
你们都过滤掉了
glare okay and that was shift a by the
好的 这是移位a
way same hot key works everywhere um and
同样的热键在任何地方都能正常工作
drop this in Okay so we've got little
把这个放进去好的 所以我们有一些
Starburst we've only got four which is
我们只有四颗星爆裂
not ideal we want as many as we can get
不是很理想 我们想要尽可能多的
really so drag it up to 16 that's better
真的 所以把它拖到16岁 这样更好
now uh there's two two values here you
现在 呃 这里有两个值 你
really want to change the first is the
真正想要改变的第一个就是
threshold that'll decide how much of the
这一门槛将决定
image is affected like as I drag this up
图像受到影响 就像我将其向上拖动时一样
in value it means only the really bright
在价值上 它只意味着真正聪明的人
stuff is going to be affected if you
如果你的话事情就会受到影响
dragged it really low then like
把它拖得很低 然后就像
everything is going to give off a star
所有的东西都会发出一颗星星
burst and it's not going to be uh what
爆裂 它不会是 呃 什么
you want and the other one is the mix
你想要的 另一种是混合
value so if you drag it all the way to
值 所以如果您将它一直拖到
one then it's going to be just the just
一次 然后它将是公正的
the effect by itself if you drag it all
如果您将其全部拖动 其本身就会产生效果
the way to minus one it's going to be
负一的方法将会是
the original render so so if you wanted
原始渲染如果您想要这样做
a nice blend between it you could go
很好的混合在一起 你可以去
like a minus. n or something and then
就像减号一样 N或其他什么然后
you've got the star burst over the top
你让星星在顶端炸开了
of the original render but if you want
原始渲染 但如果您希望
to blend this with something else I find
把这个和我发现的其他东西混在一起
it best to actually drag it the mix all
最好的办法是把它全部拖到混合体中
the way to one so that we're just
通向一号的路 所以我们只是
looking at the effect by itself um I can
看看它本身的效果 嗯 我可以
then also let me just quickly adjust the
然后也让我快速调整
threshold so that I'm only getting it in
门槛 所以我只能让它进来
the really bright places yep that's good
非常明亮的地方 是的 那很好
and
和
then um I can blend it with another
然后 嗯 我可以把它和另一种混合在一起
effect that I want so I'm going to hit
我想要的效果 所以我要去打
uh control shift d and that's going to
呃 控制移位d 这将是
duplicate it but it's going to keep it
复制它 但它会保留它
connected to my render layer here and
在这里连接到我的渲染层
then this one I'm going to make the fog
然后这一次我要制造雾
glow because looking at reference it's
发光是因为在参考文献中
not just the star burst but it's also
不仅是恒星爆炸 它还
got a uh like a glare like this glow
像这样的耀眼光芒
blurry glow coming off it so the fog
模糊的光芒从它身上散发出来 所以雾
glow is that look right it's just that
Glow是不是看起来对 只是
um and let's increase the size I think
嗯 我想让我们增加一下尺寸
and let's set the quality to high do we
让我们把质量定得高一些 好吗？
need high quality yeah I think it looks
需要高质量的 是的 我觉得它看起来
better all right all right so first to
更好的 首先
blend this all together with the the
将这一切与
render layer what we want to do is uh
渲染层我们要做的是
just like you would do in Photoshop if
就像你在Photoshop中做的那样 如果
you would use a like a blend mode you
您将使用一种类似混合模式的
would set the blend to screen or add we
会将混合设置为屏幕或添加WE
can do that by blending with shift a
可以通过与Shift a混合使用来实现
color mix mix color Okay so this we're
混色混色好的 这就是我们
going to drag in both of our glare
把我们两个人的光芒都吸引进来
effects and then instead of mix we're
效果 然后我们不是混合 而是
going to set it to add so that will just
我要将它设置为Add 这样就可以
basically ignore the black values and it
基本上忽略黑色值 它
will just take the white values and
只会把白人的价值观
combine them on the top of each other
把它们放在一起放在一起
all right now the way blender works
好了 现在搅拌机的工作方式
unlike Photoshop where it's like top to
与Photoshop不同 在Photoshop中 它就像Top to
bottom in this case it's bottom input up
在本例中是自下而上的输入
so this Factor value will will Define
因此 该系数值将定义
how bright the bottom input is okay it's
底部的输入有多亮还可以
a little weird I guess in that respect
我想在这方面有点奇怪
but so this is the strength of that
但这就是它的力量所在
bottom input um yeah so when you're
底部输入 嗯 是的 所以当你
blending something and you want to
把一些东西和你想要的混合起来
control it you just put it into the
控制它你只需要把它放进
bottom input so the streaks it's like
底部输入 所以条纹就像
it's way too heavy so I just want to go
它太重了 所以我只想走
to like a0 2 or something like that
喜欢0 2或类似的东西
really really subtle even lower goodness
真的真的很微妙甚至更低的善良
it's yeah it's really heavy this Dr I
是的 这位医生真的很重
don't know why it is so bright but I
不知道为什么它如此明亮 但我
never want it as bright as it is um okay
永远不要像现在这样明亮 嗯 好的
and now to blend it with the original
现在要把它和原版融合在一起
render for my final trick I duplicate
为我复制的最后一个戏法进行渲染
that drop it in
把它扔进去的人
here um and put this into the bottom
这里 嗯 把这个放到底部
input and I'll connect this to my
输入 我会将它连接到我的
viewer um and then let's set this to a
查看器嗯 然后让我们将其设置为
one by the way so the composite maybe I
顺便说一句 这个合成物可能是我
explain anyway the composite is going to
不管怎样 解释一下合成物将会
be what's saved into your render the
为保存到渲染中的内容
viewer is just going to be what is
观众将会是什么样子
displayed in your your background here
在这里显示在您的背景中
so if you don't have something connected
所以如果你没有关联的东西
into the composite it's not going to be
到合成物中 它不会是
saved when you do uh the render okay but
保存的时候 呃 渲染没问题 但是
that's pretty good so that's how we've
这很好 所以我们就是这么做的
got a very quick glare effect over
得到了一个非常迅速的眩光效果
everything it's a little heavy I might
每样东西都有点重 我可能
just drop it back a bit um because we
把它放在后面一点 嗯 因为我们
want it to be just like just enough that
我希望它就像是足够的
you can see it um but not crazy by the
你可以看到它 嗯 但不是疯狂的
way if you uh want to zoom in in your
如果你想放大你的
backdrop you can hit uh V will shrink
背景你可以击打呃V会缩水
the size of it and ALT V will zoom in
它的大小和Alt V将放大
they really need a better one I I agree
他们真的需要一个更好的我我同意
I agree with that um it's uh yeah it
我同意 嗯 是的 是这样的
definitely could be better I think
我想肯定可以更好
there's oh you can control it like that
哦 你可以像这样控制它
okay so if you hit your viewer node
好的 如果你点击了你的查看器节点
you've got these little uh okay you can
你有这些小的 呃 好的 你可以
do it like that as well but yeah have V
也是这样做的 但是有没有
and all V it's like a keyboard shortcut
这就像一个键盘快捷键
from the old days of blender and anyways
从过去的搅拌机时代开始 无论如何
all right um D back I don't want to go
好的 嗯 D回来 我不想去
too heavy like the thing with
太重了 就像
postprocessing when you're doing stuff
当你在做事情的时候进行后处理
in the compositor is you can like you
在排序器里是你可以喜欢你
just get like uh distracted you just get
就像 呃 分心了 你就会
like um like hypnotized by the effect
就像嗯就像被催眠的效果
and it's so common to have a render that
它是如此常见 有一个渲染
a beginner has done that's actually
一位初学者做了这件事 实际上
pretty solid but then they have just
相当可靠 但他们只是
really hammed up the post-processing
真的搞砸了后处理
effect so don't do that don't get overly
效果所以不要那样做 不要太过分
obsessed with it because um it's almost
痴迷于它因为嗯它几乎
certainly Overkill you just need to dial
当然 你只需要拨号就可以了
it back to like less than you're
它变得比你更不喜欢了
comfortable with and then it's probably
很舒服 然后很可能是
right um because whilst you're adding it
对 嗯 因为当你添加它的时候
you get really excited um anyways that's
你真的很兴奋 嗯 不管怎样 那是
what I found myself the other thing I'll
我发现自己的另一件事 我会
show you is uh if we just bring up this
向你展示一下 呃 如果我们把这个
bottom window I don't know why dope
最下面的窗户我不知道为什么要吸毒
sheet is the selected one makes no sense
工作表是选定的没有任何意义
for the uh compositing layout but if you
用于呃合成布局 但是如果你
click the little drop down the top left
点击左上角的小下拉列表
change it to 3D viewport and now in
将其更改为3D视区 现在位于
rendered mode click the little drop down
渲染模式单击小下拉菜单
next to it and you should see at the
在它旁边 你应该看到
bottom you've got options for compositor
底部 你有合成器的选择
H so let's click always and what you'll
所以让我们点击Always and What You Ware
see is that the compositing effects
看到的是合成效果
what's happening up here is now being
在这里发生的事情现在是
composed live over the top of your your
在你的上面现场作曲
viewport and this is a very new feature
这是一个非常新的功能
I think it's actually 4.0 is when it was
我认为它实际上是4.0 当它是
officially um added in um but it's it's
官方增加了这个 但这是它
huge because it means you can do and
巨大的 因为它意味着你可以做
preview your effects whilst you're
一边预览效果 一边
looking around your scene so you could
环顾你的现场 这样你就可以
like look at this like hey I can see the
就像这样 嘿 我可以看到
exact amount of that glare that's coming
即将到来的眩光的确切数量
off it um you could do you know you can
离开它 嗯 你可以做你知道你可以
do crazy stuff in the compositing and
在合成中做一些疯狂的事情
it'll it'll show through like as an
它会表现得像一个
example there's a new uh
例如 有一个新的呃
kahara uh filter that looks like this
Kahara 嗯 看起来像这样的滤镜
kind of like painterly style um and you
有点像绘画风格嗯和你
can uh yeah you can preview it like live
你能像现场直播一样预览吗？
in the 3D view it's like I feel like I'm
在3D视图中 我感觉自己像是
looking at a painting right now right
现在正在看一幅画
it's really crazy um that they that you
这真的很疯狂 嗯 他们说你
can do this real time so I'm I'm really
能实时做到这一点 所以我我真的
glad it's finally in there because it's
很高兴它终于在那里了 因为它
been uh been talked about for like a
呃 一直在谈论 就像
year I think was when it was first
我想是第一次出现的时候
previewed um so it's really cool that
预览嗯 所以这真的很酷
it's finally in here so one thing I will
它终于在这里了 所以我会做一件事
use it for actually is to check that the
使用它实际上是为了检查
threshold that I've set for the the fog
我为雾气设定的门槛
and the streaks is actually correct so
条纹实际上是正确的 所以
I'm going to look through the let's go
我要去看看我们走了
to the streaks I think streaks is pretty
对于条纹 我认为条纹很漂亮
it's a bit slow but uh anyways let's
有点慢 但不管怎样 让我们
pull in
把车开进来
here um and let's just take a look I
在这里 嗯 让我们来看看我
might have to add in a little bit okay
可能要加一点 好吗？
there we go I have to add in a little
好了 我得补充一点
bit of the original render so I can
原始渲染的一部分 这样我就可以
actually see but I just want to make
其实我看到了 但我只想做
sure that it's mostly coming through on
可以肯定的是 它大部分都是在
the metallic objects so I might actually
金属物体 所以我可能实际上
try increasing so you can see as it's
试着增加 这样你就可以看到它是
like all the way at zero you're just
就像从零开始 你只是
getting everything is going to get star
得到一切都会成为明星
beams but then as I increase it slowly
但当我慢慢地增加它的时候
slowly slowly it starts to disappear and
慢慢地 它开始消失
then the only thing that's really
那唯一真正重要的是
getting it is those metallic objects um
得到它的是那些金属物体嗯
and that's generally the look that I
这通常就是我的表情
want to go for so the okay so I went for
想去 所以可以 所以我去了
a much higher amount threshold um for
一个高得多的金额门槛
that anyways um you could have a
不管怎样 嗯 你可以有一个
different amount for the the glow but I
发光的量不同 但我
think it's generally one in the same
我觉得大体上都是一样的
effect so I think they should have the
所以我认为他们应该有
same threshold so I'm actually going to
相同的门槛 所以我实际上要
uh just Mouse over this and hit contrl C
只需将鼠标悬停在上面并按Ctrl C键即可
and then Mouse over this and hit contrl
然后将鼠标悬停在上面并按下Ctrl
V so that's how you can uh copy values
这就是你可以 呃 复制数值的方法
let me just preview that yeah the fog
让我来预告一下 是的 雾
glow looks pretty good oh it's on high
光芒看起来很不错哦 它在高处
that's why it's going to be a little bit
这就是为什么它会有一点
slow if you set it to medium I think
我想如果你把它调到中等的话速度要慢一点
it'd be a little bit more interactive um
它会更具互动性 嗯
but anyways the GPU compositing I'll say
但不管怎样 我要说的是GPU合成
is is very new um as I mentioned it's
这是非常新的 嗯 正如我所说的
it's this release and it actually for
它是这个版本 它实际上是为了
4.0 the actual final render like when
4.0实际的最终渲染 如
you hit render and it creates the 2D
你点击渲染 它就会创建2D
image um it's actually still going to be
图像 嗯 它实际上仍将是
using the CPU apparently in 4.1 maybe
在4.1中似乎使用了CPU
4.2 it will change and it'll be fully
4.2它会改变的 它会完全
GPU at that point but until then you
GPU 但在此之前
will have like slightly longer render
将会有稍微长一点的渲染
times just because of the compositor cuz
时代只因为排字 因为
the compositor is famously has been
众所周知 排字工人一直是
famously slow and blender for years it's
多年来 它以缓慢和搅拌机著称
only just now that it's uh it's being
只是刚刚才知道 呃 它是
improved so we're not really going to do
改进了 所以我们不会真的去做
a lot with a composite like I really
有很多像我这样的合成物
generally think you don't want to go
一般认为你不想去
Overkill um you can just add too many
过度杀伤力 嗯 你可以添加太多
like bells and whistles to the
就像钟声和口哨一样
compositor um but really like if you
合成者嗯 但如果你真的
want to do like drastic changes you
想要像你一样做剧烈的改变
should try to do it in the scene unless
应该试着在现场做 除非
you're doing something crazy like
你在做一些疯狂的事情 比如
spider-verse in which case it's all
蜘蛛诗 在这种情况下 一切都是
stylized right um but try to do it in
风格化的 嗯 但试着去做
the scene because um yeah I don't know I
因为那个场景 嗯 是的 我不知道我
I feel like it can be more of like a
我觉得它可以更像是
crutch you tend to like lean towards
你喜欢靠在拐杖上
like I'll fix it in the compositor I'll
就像我会把它放进排字机里一样
improve it in the compositor and it
在排序器中对其进行改进
doesn't one thing you might want to add
难道你不想补充一件事吗
is underneath uh where is it transform
在下面 呃 它在哪里变形
lens Distortion okay if you add in this
如果你把这个加进去 镜头变形没问题
node this can replicate an effect that
节点这可以复制一种效果
is actually in all cameras as well and
实际上也出现在所有的摄像机中
that's lens Distortion all right so you
这是镜头变形好的所以你
can see uh it actually makes more sense
可以看到 呃 它实际上更有意义
to actually see it on the 2D image um so
在2D图像上实际看到它 嗯 所以
I'll put that in the background there um
我会把它放在背景里 嗯
but basically where the edges of a uh a
但基本上 一个呃a的边缘
shot it's like if you take a photo with
拍摄就像是和你合影
your iPhone on like a w it's most
你的iPhone就像是开着它是最
visible on like wider lenses but the uh
可以在更宽的镜片上看到 但是呃
straight vertical things start to look
垂直的东西开始看起来
bent um and it's just it's Barrel
弯曲的嗯 它只是它的桶
Distortion and there's no way to get
失真 没有办法得到
around it unless you use a pinhole
绕过它 除非你用针孔
camera it's it's kind of interesting
相机 这很有趣
thing but it's it's all because of the
但这一切都是因为
Optics of the lens that bends the the
使透镜弯曲的透镜的光学特性
objects like that um so anyways it is in
像这样的物体 嗯 所以不管怎样 它在
all objects uh it does though because
所有的物体 呃 它确实是这样的 因为
it's a like a post effect it does kind
这就像是一种后效 它确实是一种
of blow so it's like manipulating those
所以这就像是操纵那些
pixels so it means those pixels aren't
像素 所以这意味着这些像素不是
going to be as sharp so I generally
会变得一样锋利 所以我通常
don't like it for that reason um but if
我不喜欢 因为这个原因 嗯 但是如果
you wanted to you could add this just
如果你想 你可以添加这个
keep it really low like a 0.1 amount
把它保持在非常低的水平 比如0.1%
with fit so that it doesn't get that uh
这样它就不会得到那个呃
you know TV screen look on the edges and
你知道 电视屏幕的边缘看起来
then the other thing you could add is a
然后您可以添加的另一件事是
little bit of chromatic aberration um
一点点色差
I'll show you just uh yeah this is what
我来给你演示一下 嗯 是的 这就是
that does so you can see this is where
这样你就可以看到这就是
it turned up a lot you can see the edges
它出现了很多 你可以看到边缘
of the objects right it has this kind of
物体的权利 它有这样一种
uh the red and the cyan and the red and
呃 红色和青色 红色和
the yellow it like towards the edges of
它就像是朝向边缘的黄色
it it gets this um yeah this kind of
它得到了这种 嗯 是的 这种
separation of the colors and that is
颜色的分离 那就是
again a naturally occurring thing that
这又是一件自然发生的事情
happens with cameras because of the
相机会发生这种情况 因为
Optics um and the cheaper the Optics the
光学嗯和更便宜的光学
cheaper the lens the more likely it's to
镜片越便宜 越有可能
happen um but it is there I try not to
发生了 但它就在那里 我试着不去做
use it because it can be very overused
使用它 因为它可能会被过度使用
and very like I don't just makes it look
而且我不仅仅是让它看起来
cheap like hey this person just
就像嘿 这个人只是
discovered there's the chromatic
发现那里有一张彩色的
apparation but if you are going to use
幻影 但如果你要使用
it go really low really low like because
它很低很低 就像是因为
actually this you have to think of the
实际上这一点你必须考虑到
story of the shot and someone has like
关于枪击的故事 有人喜欢
framed this shot beautifully got
把这张照片框起来 拍得漂亮
beautiful sunlight right this is a
美丽的阳光 对 这是一个
professional professional has taken this
专业人士拍了这张照片
photograph of the donuts on the counter
柜台上甜甜圈的照片
they're not going to be using using a
他们不会使用
cheap lens so although there might be
便宜的镜片 所以尽管可能有
some chromatic aberration it'll be very
一些色差 它将是非常
very uh minimal um but if you want that
非常 呃 最小的 但是如果你想要的话
um you know what I I'll keep it in yeah
嗯 你知道吗 我会把它藏起来的
why not we'll keep it in um but yeah
为什么不呢 我们会把它保存在嗯 但是
that's basically what I'm going to do
这基本上就是我要做的
for this so this is my final node setup
因此 这是我的最终节点设置
if you'd like to copy it have ADD it the
如果您想复制它 请将它添加到
final thing I'll mention as well is if
最后我要提的是 如果
you want to disable your composit like
你想禁用你的组合 就像
say you're doing some renders and you
假设你在做一些渲染 而你
don't you just want to see it without
你不是只想在没有
the post-processing effects on top of it
其上的后处理效果
um rather than having to come in here
嗯 而不是非得来这里
and then like you know reconnect and
然后就像你知道的那样重新连接
disconnect a bunch of nodes um instead
断开一堆节点嗯
if you just go to your what's that the
如果你只是去你的那是什么
output property settings way at the
输出属性设置方式
bottom you've got postprocessing so if
底部有后处理 所以如果
you just uncheck compositing that means
您只需取消勾选合成 这意味着
you're only going to be seeing the
你只会看到
original render um and then check it
原始渲染嗯然后检查一下
again and it's going to be uh kicking in
再次 它将会呃开始发挥作用
whatever is uh in your compositing
无论你的合成中有什么
settings but that's it for this video
设置 但本视频的仅此而已
click here to watch the next part and I
点击这里观看下一部分 我
will see you there
我会在那里见到你